George Korson Collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
George Korson collection circa 1880s-1980 circa 1930s-1967
AFC 2003/011
Korson, George Gershon, 1899-1967
37,117 items; 106 containers (not including AV); 57 linear feet (not including AV).
112 sound discs: analog; 12 in., 10 in., and 7 in.
108 sound tape reels: analog; 7 in.
6 sound tape reels: analog; 5 in.
1 sound cassette: analog
1 film reel (ca. 8 minutes): sound, black and white; 16 mm
approximately 623 photographs: photographic prints, negatives, black and white; various sizes.
4 graphic items: various media.
2 items.
36,259 items.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of professional papers, field recordings of interviews and songs, a film, and photographs documenting the career and folklife fieldwork of George Korson. George Korson conducted fieldwork in the anthracite coal region of Pennsylvania and also in Pennsylvania Dutch Country in eastern counties of Pennsylvania. The film dated October 12, 1964 is George Korson (with Charlie McCarthy) interviewed by Franklin D. Coslett. The collection also includes various papers and interviews created by Angus K. Gillespie, including his interviews with folklorist and labor historian Archie Green. Gillespie is the author of a biography of George Korson, titled Folklorist of the coal fields: George Korson's life and work (Pennsylvania State University Press, 1980).
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Collins, Fletcher, Jr., 1906-2005--Interviews.; Eskin, Sam--Interviews.; Gillespie, Angus K., 1942-; Green, Archie--Interviews.; Hand, Wayland D. (Wayland Debs), 1907-1986--Interviews.; Korson, George Gershon, 1899-1967; Korson, George Gershon, 1899-1967--Correspondence.; Korson, George Gershon, 1899-1967--Interviews.; Korson, George Gershon, 1899-1967. Coal dust on the fiddle; songs and stories of the bituminous industry.; Lewis, John L. (John Llewellyn), 1880-1969.
Organizations
American Red Cross.; Molly Maguires (Organization); Pennsylvania Folk Festival (1935: Allentown, Pa.); Pennsylvania Folk Festival (1936: Lewisburg, Pa.); United Mine Workers of America.
Subjects
Ballads, English.; Children's songs, English.; Coal miners--Pennsylvania--Folklore.; Coal miners--Pennsylvania--Interviews.; Coal miners--Songs and music.; Folk festivals--United States.; Folk music--Pennsylvania.; Folk songs, English--Pennsylvania--Texts.; Folk songs, English--Pennsylvania.; Folklore--Pennsylvania.; Folklorists--United States--Correspondence.; Folklorists--United States--Photographs.; Irish Americans--Pennsylvania.; Labor unions--Folklore.; Labor unions--Songs and music.; Labor unions--United States--History.; Miners--Songs and music.; Miners--United States--Folklore.; Pennsylvania Dutch--Pennsylvania--Folklore.
Titles
Former title from King's College Library: George Korson folklore archive
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Field notes.; Interviews.; Lectures.; Legends.; Manuscripts for publication.; Manuscripts.; Maps.; Oral histories.; Photographs.; Poems.; Radio programs.; Scrapbooks.; Songs.; Sound recordings.
Arrangement
Organized by format into the following series: 1. Manuscripts; 2. Sound Recordings; 3. Graphic Materials; 4. Moving Images; 5. Artifacts.
Acquisition
King's College, Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania; 2003.
Custodial History
The George Korson Folklore Archive was presented by George Korson to King's College, Wilkes Barre, Pennsylvania in 1965 and donated by King's College to the American Folklife Center in 2003.
Related Material
The American Folklife Center has four more George Korson collections: George Korson collection of songs of bituminous coal miners (AFC 1963/004), George Korson recording of songs from Pennsylvania (AFC 1958/007), George Korson recordings of Pennsylvania coal miners (AFC 1948/004), and Robert Sayers collection of George Korson publicity photographs for the Pennsylvania Folk Festival, 1936 (AFC 1982/012).
Angus K. Gillespie Papers, 1979-2002, at the Special Collections and University Archives, Rutgers University Libraries http://www2.scc.rutgers.edu/ead/uarchives/gillespie_tpk_twinf.html
Separated Material
A subset of published materials (books and magazines) was kept with the collection; see Appendix A for details. The card catalog (Box 95) has the full list of books and magazines from the George Korson Folklore Archive.
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Access may be restricted. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Additional Formats
Selected analog recordings have digital preservation masters.
Biographical Note
George Korson, folklorist, journalist, and labor historian, was born in 1899 in Ukraine, and came with his family to the U.S. in 1906. He began his working life as a journalist, and subsequently wrote several books on the songs and folklore of coal miners in Pennsylvania and West Virginia. Korson was an advocate for the rights of miners and improved working conditions for them. In 1957 he was awarded a Guggenheim Fellowship to write the book Black Rock. He was a president of the American Red Cross, served three terms as president of the Pennsylvania Folklore Society, and was elected a Fellow of the American Folklore Society in 1960. He died in 1967.
Scope and Content
Collection of professional papers, field recordings of interviews and songs, a film, and photographs documenting the career and folklife fieldwork of George Korson. George Korson conducted fieldwork in the anthracite coal region of Pennsylvania and also in Pennsylvania Dutch Country in eastern counties of Pennsylvania. The film dated October 12, 1964 is George Korson (with Charlie McCarthy) interviewed by Franklin D. Coslett. The collection also includes various papers and interviews created by Angus K. Gillespie, including his interviews with folklorist and labor historian Archie Green. Gillespie is the author of a biography of George Korson, titled Folklorist of the coal fields: George Korson's life and work (Pennsylvania State University Press, 1980).
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Subseries A: Administrative materials
    - A Description of the George Korson Folklore Archive (Box-folder 1/1)
      The published version of the inventory at King's College, compiled by Judith Tierney. No. 1 in the Wyoming Valley Series, of the Publications of the D. Leonard Corgan Library; Mary Barrett, ed. (1973).
    - Manuscript materials accompanying sound recordings (Box-folder 1/2)
      Includes disc labels that detached from disc centers, as well as typed song lists and handwritten notes.
    - Sound recordings: disc labels and centers (photocopies) (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Subseries B: Biographical materials
    - Discharge certificate, 38th Battalion, Royal Fusiliers, British Army, 1919 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Certificate of naturalization, November 13, 1928 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Application for Guggenheim grant, 1938 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Employment application, 1941 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - American Red Cross: European tour (1 of 2), 1946 (Box-folder 2/5)
      Includes orders, notebook, passport, etc.
    - American Red Cross: European tour (2 of 2), 1946 (Box-folder 2/6)
      See description for box-folder 2/5.
    - American Red Cross: campaign fund, 1953 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - American Red Cross Courier: certificate of excellence; letters of commendation, etc., 1948-1952 (Box-folder 2/8)
      American Red Cross Courier was the magazine of the American Red Cross. In addition to the certificate and letters is an illustrated booklet for the American Institute of Graphic Arts exhibition, 1951; on pages 11 and 26 are listings for issues of the Courier, for which George Korson is one of the editors. The materials in this folder are listed in the King's College Library inventory as preceding the "Miscellany" folder. The materials were received at the American Folklife Center with the folder in its present position in the order of folders, and with the original notation on the folder back (regarding the order of folders within a box) erased and rewritten.
    - American Red Cross: certificate of meritorious service, 1946 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - American Red Cross: miscellaneous receipts, expense accounts, etc., 1949-1950 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - American Red Cross: miscellaneous office memoranda, 1942-1954 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - American Red Cross: minutes of staff meetings, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - American Red Cross: miscellaneous (1 of 3), circa 1945-1966 (Box-folder 2/13)
      Includes position descriptions and work evaluations for jobs with the American Red Cross held by Korson and others, typescripts of speeches and writings by Korson, photostat copies of newspaper clippings, typed copies of telegrams, a newsprint clipping, a B'nai B'rith News Service publication on the relationship between the organization and the Red Cross, a handbook for American Red Cross chapters, etc.
    - American Red Cross: miscellaneous (2 of 3), circa 1945-1966 (Box-folder 2/14)
      See description for box-folder 2/13.
    - American Red Cross: miscellaneous (3 of 3), circa 1945-1966 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Application for Guggenheim grant, 1947 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Employment application, 1950 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Employment application, post-1961 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Miscellany (1 of 2), circa 1917-1931 (Box-folder 3/4)
      Resume drafts and related documents, newspaper clipping announcing engagement of Rae Korson (then Rachel Rosenblatt) to George Korson, the handwritten text of Korson's part in a debate speech, an account book for George Korson, etc.
    - Miscellany (2 of 2), circa 1917-1931 (Box-folder 3/5)
      See description for box-folder 3/4.
  - Subseries C: Correspondence
    There are no correspondence folders for the following dates: December 1939, March 1942, August 1951, August 1952, and June-November 1967.
    - Correspondence, 1918-1929 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Correspondence, 1930 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Correspondence, 1931 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Correspondence, 1932 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Correspondence, 1933 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Correspondence, April 1934 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Correspondence, June 1934 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Correspondence, July 1934 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Correspondence, August 1934 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Correspondence, September 1934 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Correspondence, October 1934 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Correspondence, November 1934 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Correspondence, December 1934 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Correspondence, January 1935 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Correspondence, February 1935 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Correspondence, March 1935 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), April 1935 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), April 1935 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Correspondence, May 1935 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Correspondence, June 1935 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Correspondence, July 1935 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Correspondence, August 1935 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Correspondence, September 1935 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Correspondence, October 1935 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Correspondence, November 1935 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Correspondence, December 1935 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Correspondence, circa 1935 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Correspondence, January 1936 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Correspondence, February 1936 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Correspondence, March 1-15, 1936 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Correspondence, March 16-31, 1936 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Correspondence, April 1-15, 1936 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Correspondence, April 16-30, 1936 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Correspondence, May 1-15, 1936 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Correspondence, May 16-31, 1936 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Correspondence, June 1-10, 1936 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Correspondence, June 11-20, 1936 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Correspondence, June 21-30, 1936 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Correspondence, July 1-5, 1936 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Correspondence, July 6-10, 1936 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Correspondence, July 11-15, 1936 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Correspondence, July 16-20, 1936 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Correspondence, July 21-25, 1936 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Correspondence, July 26-31, 1936 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Correspondence, August 1936 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Correspondence, September 1936 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Correspondence, October 1936 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Correspondence, November 1936 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Correspondence, December 1936 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Correspondence, circa 1936 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Correspondence, January 1937 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Correspondence, February 1937 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Correspondence, March 1937 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), April 1937 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), April 1937 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), May 1-15, 1937 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), May 1-15, 1937 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), May 16-31, 1937 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), May 16-31, 1937 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), June 1-15, 1937 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), June 1-15, 1937 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), June 16-30, 1937 (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), June 16-30, 1937 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), July 1-10, 1937 (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), July 1-10, 1937 (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), July 11-20, 1937 (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), July 11-20, 1937 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), July 21-25, 1937 (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), July 21-25, 1937 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), July 26-31, 1937 (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), July 26-31, 1937 (Box-folder 8/14)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), August 1937 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), August 1937 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Correspondence, September 1937 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Correspondence, October 1937 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Correspondence, November 1937 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Correspondence, December 1937 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Correspondence (1 of 2), circa 1937 (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Correspondence (2 of 2), circa 1937 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Correspondence, January 1938 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Correspondence, February 1938 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Correspondence, March 1938 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Correspondence, April 1938 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Correspondence, May 1938 (Box-folder 9/13)
    - Correspondence, June 1938 (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Correspondence, July 1938 (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Correspondence, August 1938 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Correspondence, September 1938 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Correspondence, October 1938 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Correspondence, November 1938 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Correspondence, December 1938 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Correspondence, circa 1938 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Correspondence, January 1939 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Correspondence, February 1939 (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Correspondence, March 1939 (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Correspondence, April 1939 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Correspondence, May 1939 (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Correspondence, June 1939 (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Correspondence, July 1939 (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Correspondence, August 1939 (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Correspondence, September 1939 (Box-folder 10/15)
    - Correspondence, October 1939 (Box-folder 10/16)
    - Correspondence, November 1939 (Box-folder 10/17)
    - Correspondence, January 1940 (Box-folder 10/18)
    - Correspondence, February 1940 (Box-folder 10/19)
    - Correspondence, March 1940 (Box-folder 10/20)
    - Correspondence, April 1940 (Box-folder 10/21)
    - Correspondence, May 1940 (Box-folder 10/22)
    - Correspondence, June 1940 (Box-folder 10/23)
    - Correspondence, July 1940 (Box-folder 10/24)
    - Correspondence, August 1940 (Box-folder 10/25)
    - Correspondence, September 1940 (Box-folder 10/26)
    - Correspondence, October 1940 (Box-folder 10/27)
    - Correspondence, November 1940 (Box-folder 10/28)
    - Correspondence, December 1940 (Box-folder 10/29)
    - Correspondence, circa 1940 (Box-folder 10/30)
    - Correspondence, January 1941 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Correspondence, February 1941 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Correspondence, March 1941 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Correspondence, April 1941 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Correspondence, May 1941 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Correspondence, June 1941 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Correspondence, July-August, 1941 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Correspondence, September 1941 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Correspondence, October 1941 (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Correspondence, November 1941 (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Correspondence, December 1941 (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Correspondence, January 1942 (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Correspondence, February 1942 (Box-folder 11/13)
    - Correspondence, April 1942 (Box-folder 11/14)
    - Correspondence, May 1942 (Box-folder 11/15)
    - Correspondence, June 1942 (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Correspondence, July 1942 (Box-folder 11/17)
    - Correspondence, August 1942 (Box-folder 11/18)
    - Correspondence, September 1942 (Box-folder 11/19)
    - Correspondence, October 1942 (Box-folder 11/20)
    - Correspondence, November 1942 (Box-folder 11/21)
    - Correspondence, December 1942 (Box-folder 11/22)
    - Correspondence, January 1943 (Box-folder 11/23)
    - Correspondence, February 1943 (Box-folder 11/24)
    - Correspondence, March 1943 (Box-folder 11/25)
    - Correspondence, April 1943 (Box-folder 11/26)
    - Correspondence, May 1943 (Box-folder 11/27)
    - Correspondence, June 1943 (Box-folder 11/28)
    - Correspondence, July 1943 (Box-folder 11/29)
    - Correspondence, August 1943 (Box-folder 11/30)
    - Correspondence, September 1943 (Box-folder 11/31)
    - Correspondence, October 1943 (Box-folder 11/32)
    - Correspondence, November 1943 (Box-folder 11/33)
    - Correspondence, December 1943 (Box-folder 11/34)
    - Correspondence, January 1944 (Box-folder 11/35)
    - Correspondence, February 1944 (Box-folder 11/36)
    - Correspondence, March 1944 (Box-folder 11/37)
    - Correspondence, April 1944 (Box-folder 11/38)
    - Correspondence, May 1944 (Box-folder 11/39)
    - Correspondence, June 1944 (Box-folder 11/40)
    - Correspondence, July 1944 (Box-folder 11/41)
    - Correspondence, August 1944 (Box-folder 11/42)
    - Correspondence, September 1944 (Box-folder 11/43)
    - Correspondence, October 1944 (Box-folder 11/44)
    - Correspondence, November 1944 (Box-folder 11/45)
    - Correspondence, December 1944 (Box-folder 11/46)
    - Correspondence, January 1945 (Box-folder 11/47)
    - Correspondence, February 1945 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Correspondence, March 1945 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Correspondence, April 1945 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Correspondence, May 1945 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Correspondence, June 1945 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Correspondence, July 1945 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Correspondence, August 1945 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Correspondence, September 1945 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Correspondence, October 1945 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Correspondence, November 1945 (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Correspondence, December 1945 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Correspondence, January 1946 (Box-folder 12/12)
    - Correspondence, February 1946 (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Correspondence, March 1946 (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Correspondence, April 1946 (Box-folder 12/15)
    - Correspondence, May 1946 (Box-folder 12/16)
    - Correspondence, June 1946 (Box-folder 12/17)
    - Correspondence, July 1946 (Box-folder 12/18)
    - Correspondence, August 1946 (Box-folder 12/19)
    - Correspondence, September 1946 (Box-folder 12/20)
    - Correspondence, October 1946 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Correspondence, November 1946 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Correspondence, December 1946 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Correspondence, January 1947 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Correspondence, February 1947 (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Correspondence, March 1947 (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Correspondence, April 1947 (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Correspondence, May 1947 (Box-folder 13/8)
    - Correspondence, June 1947 (Box-folder 13/9)
    - Correspondence, July 1947 (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Correspondence, August 1947 (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Correspondence, September 1947 (Box-folder 13/12)
    - Correspondence, October 1947 (Box-folder 13/13)
    - Correspondence, November 1947 (Box-folder 13/14)
    - Correspondence, December 1947 (Box-folder 13/15)
    - Correspondence, circa 1947 (Box-folder 13/16)
    - Correspondence, January 1948 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Correspondence, February 1948 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Correspondence, March 1948 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Correspondence, April 1948 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Correspondence, May 1948 (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Correspondence, June 1948 (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Correspondence, July 1948 (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Correspondence, August 1948 (Box-folder 14/8)
      Includes a typed note (signed) from Helen Hartness Flanders to Rae Korson, signed by Flanders.
    - Correspondence, September 1948 (Box-folder 14/9)
    - Correspondence, October 1948 (Box-folder 14/10)
    - Correspondence, November 1948 (Box-folder 14/11)
    - Correspondence, December 1948 (Box-folder 14/12)
    - Correspondence, circa 1948 (Box-folder 14/13)
    - Correspondence, January 1949 (Box-folder 14/14)
    - Correspondence, February 1949 (Box-folder 14/15)
    - Correspondence, March 1949 (Box-folder 14/16)
    - Correspondence, April 1949 (Box-folder 14/17)
    - Correspondence, May 1949 (Box-folder 14/18)
    - Correspondence, June 1949 (Box-folder 14/19)
    - Correspondence, July 1949 (Box-folder 14/20)
    - Correspondence, August 1949 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Correspondence, September 1949 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Correspondence, October 1949 (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Correspondence, November 1949 (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Correspondence, December 1949 (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Correspondence, circa 1949 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Correspondence, January 1950 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Correspondence, February 1950 (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Correspondence, March 1950 (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Correspondence, April 1950 (Box-folder 15/10)
    - Correspondence, May 1950 (Box-folder 15/11)
    - Correspondence, June 1950 (Box-folder 15/12)
    - Correspondence, July 1950 (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Correspondence, August 1950 (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Correspondence, September 1950 (Box-folder 15/15)
    - Correspondence, October 1950 (Box-folder 15/16)
    - Correspondence, November 1950 (Box-folder 15/17)
    - Correspondence, December 1950 (Box-folder 15/18)
    - Correspondence, January 1951 (Box-folder 15/19)
    - Correspondence, February 1951 (Box-folder 15/20)
    - Correspondence, March 1951 (Box-folder 15/21)
    - Correspondence, April 1951 (Box-folder 15/22)
    - Correspondence, May 1951 (Box-folder 15/23)
    - Correspondence, June 1951 (Box-folder 15/24)
    - Correspondence, July 1951 (Box-folder 15/25)
    - Correspondence, September 1951 (Box-folder 15/26)
    - Correspondence, October 1951 (Box-folder 15/27)
    - Correspondence, November-December 1951 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Correspondence, January 1952 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Correspondence, February 1952 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Correspondence, March 1952 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Correspondence, April 1952 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Correspondence, May 1952 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Correspondence, June 1952 (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Correspondence, July 1952 (Box-folder 16/8)